各位  星球大战日马上就要到了
Gentlemen, Star Wars day is rapidly approaching.
我们得定下计划啦
We should finalize our plans.
什么  还真有这玩意啊
What? That's a real thing?
是哪天  星球大战圣诞节吗
What is it, Star Wars Christmas?
不是  你说什么傻话
No. Don't be ridiculous.
那天是伍基人生命日好吗
That's Wookiee Life Day.
所以是哪天
So, when is it?
不是5月5号
Uh, well, it's not May the fifth...
也不是5月3号
and it's not May the third...
是5月4号
It's May the fourth.
懂没
Get it?
5月4号[愿原力]与你同在
May the fourth be with you?
"愿原力与你同在"  懂了吗
"May the force be with you." Get it?
你误会了  我这表情不是因为不懂
Oh, no. This face wasn't because I didn't get it.
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
校对：每周锁定秀恩爱字幕组
总监   YY猫
请进
Come in.
-你有空吗  -有啊
- Hey, you got a second? - Yes.
刚好我也想找你
Actually, I'm glad you're here.
我在定星球大战日的行程
I-I'm working on the Star Wars Day schedule.
我在《星球大战I：幽灵的威胁》播放完后
Now, I have a window built in after Phantom Menace,
留了吐槽这部的时间  但...
for complaining, but...
我怕一小时会不够
I'm worried an hour won't be enough time.
谢尔顿  我有个坏消息
Sheldon, I-I've got some bad news.
什么坏消息
What is it?
我刚在网上看到
I just read online
亚瑟·杰弗里斯先生过世了
that Arthur Jeffries passed away.
质子教授去世了吗
Professor Proton is dead?
兄弟  节哀
Sorry, buddy.
你在闹哪样
What are you doing?
安慰你啊
Comforting you?
你的心意可能对了
Y-Your heart might be in the right place,
但是你的头  胸  手臂  绝对放错地方了
but your head, chest and arms certainly aren't.
总之  葬礼是在周日
Anyway, the-the funeral's on Sunday.
可是那天是星球大战日啊
But, that's Star Wars Day.
是啊  可是...
Yeah... um...
在所有该为这消息难过的原因中
of all the things about this that are sad,
撞日应该排不到第一吧
that might not be number one.
你还好吗  我知道他对你很重要
You okay? I know he meant a lot to you.
我没事
I'm fine.
好吧
Okay.
葡萄干麦片盒换封面的时候  他倒哭了
Yet he cried when they changed the Raisin Bran box.
小朋友们  跟你们说个有意思的
This, uh, this is something interesting boys and girls.
在猫头鹰进食完后  它们会以小球状
After an owl eats, he spits up part of his meal,
吐出它们消化不了的食物
that he can't digest, in the form of a pellet.
是不是很令人"呜呜"大笑
Is-Isn't that a hoot?
节目将在我炒了我的编剧后回来
We'll be right back after I fire my writers.
闭上你的鸟嘴
Oh, shut up.
在看你的老朋友吗
Watching your old friend?
是啊
Yes.
艾米  你看他
Look at him, Amy.
太可惜了
It's such a shame.
在我的英年  他就这么去了
Struck down in the prime of my life.
你想我陪你一起去参加丧礼吗
Do you want me to go to the funeral with you?
我才不去那丧礼
Oh, I'm not going to the funeral.
为什么
Why not?
这么多人在擤鼻涕
All those people blowing their noses.
分不出哪个是在哭  哪个在生病
You can't tell the sick from the sad. Mm.
我会在家按照原定计划  庆祝星球大战日
I'll be at home celebrating Star Wars Day, as planned.
你确定你不想去跟他道别吗
Are you sure you don't want to go say good-bye?
人生自古谁无死  省了吊唁不作死
Amy, mourning the inevitable is a complete waste of time.
那看一堆你看过几百次的
And watching a bunch of goofy space movies
宅爆太空电影就不作死吗
you've seen hundreds of times isn't?
如果我们是有肉体关系的情侣
If we were in a physical relationship,
你那句话就害你今晚没得爱爱了
you just lost sex tonight.
你们好啊
Hey, guys.
佩妮  星球大战日快乐
Hey, Penny. Happy Star Wars Day.
好
Okay.
我能为你做早餐吗
Can I make you breakfast?
阿克"巴"上将的小吃"吧"  欢喜营业中
Admiral Ackbar's Snack Bar is open for business.
不用了  谢谢  我要跟莱纳德去参加丧礼呢
No, thanks. Leonard and I are just going to the funeral.
确定吗  咖啡也不要吗
You sure. Not even coffee?
有R2-D[低]咖啡因咖啡哦
We have R2-Decaf.
或是来一杯欧"莉亚"咖啡
Maybe a nice Cafe Au Leia?
欧蕾咖啡  加入大量牛奶的咖啡
莉亚  星球大战中的一位人类公主
如果你没有喝咖啡的心情
And if you're not in the mood for coffee,
我也可以给你泡杯印度T[茶]3PO
I can always make you a Chai Tea-3PO.
我懂了  就像是C-3PO
Oh, I get it-- like C-3PO.
我怎么会堕落至此
What happened to me?
谢尔顿  你想来点什么吗
Hey, uh, Sheldon, you want anything?
不用了  谢谢
Uh, no, thank you.
你今天好安静
You're being so quiet.
你是心里难过  还是你个机械人在重启
Are you upset or are you just rebooting?
我没事
I'm fine.
亲爱的  你确定你今天
Sweetie, are you sure you don't want to
不跟我们一起去丧礼吗
come with us to the funeral?
谢谢你的邀请  但亚瑟已经死了
Oh, I appreciate the offer, but Arthur is gone
我就算去了也做不到什么
and there's nothing I can do about it.
黑武士杀了欧比旺的时候
When Darth Vader struck down Obi-Wan,
卢克有哭天喊地  然后去参加丧礼吗
did Luke cry like a baby and go to his funeral?
没有
No.
他把死星炸了
He blew up the Death Star.
我怎么会知道这个啊
Why do I know this?!
亚瑟·杰弗里斯是个科学家
Arthur Jeffries was a scientist.
我相信他不是个会在意
I'm sure he didn't care about
丧礼这种无聊事的人
silly superstitions like funerals.
如果他今天有来  他一定会说
You know, if he were here, I think he'd say,
"祝你们星球大战日玩得开心"
"Enjoy Star Wars Day."
他都84岁了  他会说的是"我的布丁呢"
He was 84; he'd say, "where's my pudding?"
你们走之前  让我帮你们打包点
Before you go, at least let me pack you some
司康的进攻  让你们路上吃吧
Attack of the Scones for the road.
《星战2: 克隆人的进攻》的双关嘛
Oh, like Attack of the Clones.
我们现在就走
We are leaving right now.
亚瑟去世的消息对谢尔顿的打击很大
Arthur passing away was harder on Sheldon
但是他不愿意承认
than he's ready to admit.
真心希望这个能让他开心点
Really hoping this will cheer him up.
我也是
Me, too.
我们烤这个名字带"死"字的死星
Although, it might've been thoughtless of us
会不会有点不好
to bake a Death Star cake.
不会啊  这包含了两样他最爱的事物
No, it combines two of Sheldon's favorite things:
巧克力碎
chocolate chips
还有按个按钮就能摧毁个星球的能力
and the ability to destroy a planet at the push of a button.
无论如何  这给男生们当惊喜也挺好
Well, anyway, it'll be a nice surprise for the boys.
华仔一直觉得我不把他的爱好当回事
And Howie doesn't think I take his interests seriously,
希望这个蛋糕能唬住他一阵子
so hopefully this will keep him fooled for a while.
拿上翻糖开始裱花吧
Okay, let's get the fondant and start decorating.
这挺酷的
This is pretty cool.
球体的蛋糕挺罕见呢
You don't see too many spherical cakes.
原因大概就是这个吧
I wonder why that is.
我想坦白一件事
I have a confession to make.
我从来没参加过丧礼
I've never been to a funeral before.
真的吗
Really?
我还没碰过认识的人过世
I just never knew anyone that died.
我小时候有一只宠物猪
I had a pet pig when I was a kid.
它死掉的时候没有办丧礼
I mean, when he died, we didn't have a funeral,
我们把它烤了
we had a barbecue.
放心吧  今晚不会把亚瑟烤了吃的
Yeah, we won't be eating Arthur tonight.
我虽然跟他不熟  但我挺喜欢他呢
I didn't know him very well, but I still really liked him.
他就这么去了  感觉好奇怪
It's weird that he's... just gone.
我明白
I know.
我感觉好想哭
I feel like I want to cry.
没事的
Oh... that's-that's fine.
哭吧哭吧
Go ahead.
-你盯着我  我哭不出来  -抱歉
- I can't do it with you staring at me. - Sorry.
不行  没眼泪
No, I'm dry.
你整天哭哭啼啼  你先开场  我再加入
You're a big crybaby-- you start, I'll join in.
我才没整天哭哭啼啼
I am not a crybaby.
看《玩具总动员3》时呢
Toy Story 3?
玩具们在焚化炉里手牵手等死呢
The toys were holding hands in a furnace!
亚瑟这一辈子过得很充实
Look, A-Arthur lived a full life.
他鼓舞了很多人
And he inspired a lot of people.
的确  他是我儿时的偶像
Sure, he-he was my childhood hero,
但我后来有机会能与他
but... the fact that I got to work with him,
有共事的机会  在他...
side by side, before he...
去世之前...
died was...
真的...  是老天的赏赐
it was... it was a gift.
的确是老天的赏赐
It was a gift.
谢谢你在我们的感情中
Thank you for being the emotional one
当多愁善感的那个
in this relationship.
-一切有我  -是啊
- I got your back. - Yeah.
好了  准备开始
Okay, here we go.
第一部  《幽灵的威胁》
Episode I-- The Phantom Menace.
赶紧看完了事吧
Let's get this over with.
既然我们大家都同意不喜欢第一部
Since we all agree Episode I isn't our favorite,
我们这次何不直接跳过呢
maybe we just skip it this time.
霍华德  我觉得所有人中
Yeah, Howard, I think you of all people
你最不应该有
should avoid espousing the principle
如果不喜欢某事物
that if something is not our favorite
就让它滚的心态
we should just get rid of it.
我听说过一种看星战电影的方法
You know, I heard this way of watching the movies
叫弯刀顺序  先看第五第六部
called the Machete Order, where you watch Episodes IV and V,
然后跳过第一部
then skip Episode I,
把第二第三部当闪回看
watch II and III as a flashback,
然后看第四部做完结
and then finish with VI.
所以加加大多数的戏份
Okay, so you'd lose most of Jar Jar,
贸易路线与无聊的议会审讯戏全没了
all the trade route talk, and the boring senate hearings,
那无聊程度跟看公共事务台有得一拼
which are like watching C-SPAN with monsters.
跳过贸易路线部分吗
Get rid of the trade route part?
那帕尔帕庭是怎么把
Then how would Palpatine
瓦洛伦议长搞下台  再夺位的
get Chancellor Valorum kicked out of office?
少了那部分剧情  他会是怎么选上的
How would he get himself elected? How?
我们就不能过上一个
Can we get through one holiday
没有你胡言乱语的节日吗
without you saying something ridiculous?
只是个建议嘛
It was just a suggestion.
你知道还有什么事也只是个建议吗
Well, you know what else was just a suggestion?
"要不我们换一下早餐麦片盒的封面吧"
"Why don't we change the Raisin Bran box?"
你知道谁因此内心受伤了吗
Hmm? And you know who got hurt by that?
所有吃那个早餐的人啊
Every single person who eats breakfast!
我想质子教授的去世对他打击很大吧
I think he's taking this Professor Proton thing pretty hard.
我们该去开导他吗
Should we try to console him?
或者我们应该尊重他
Or... should we respect his privacy
内心哀伤时期的隐私
in this moment of grief?
就乖乖坐在这里看电影就行了
By staying here and watching the movie.
好朋友都会这么做啊
That's what good friends would do!
好歹因为谢尔顿不在这
Well, at least without Sheldon here,
我们可以从第四部开始看
we got to start with Episode IV.
是啊
Mm, true.
我心里对他挺过意不去的
I do feel guilty about him.
我也是
Me, too.
我们去看看他怎么样了吧
Maybe we should see how he's doing.
好啊
Yeah.
-等酒吧这一段看完再去吧  -必须的
- But after the cantina scene. - Obviously.
看看亚瑟
Look at Arthur...
被我的笑话逗得捧腹大笑
cracking up at a joke I told him.
我再也听不到他的笑声了
I'll never hear that laugh again.
那次我也没笑
You never heard it that time.
亚瑟
Arthur!
-我以为你死了  -是的
- I thought you were dead. - I am.
感觉好极了
Oh, it-it's fantastic.
这是多年来我第一次
I mean, this is the longest that I've gone
这么长时间不需要总是跑厕所
without running into a men's room in-in years.
你怎么会来我家
Why are you here?
我也不知道
I-I don't know. I was...
我本希望去我前妻家吓唬她的
I was hoping I was going to haunt my ex-wife.
我知道原因了
I know why.
你之所以来找我  是因为
You've come to me because
你是我的欧比旺[绝地武士]
you're my Obi-Wan.
我不...我不懂你在说什么
I'm-I'm not... I'm not familiar with that.
那...是不是...
Is... is-is that an...
就是互联网啊
an Internet?
鸡同鸭讲
Wow.
算了  我就不跟死人计较了
Uh, you're dead, so I'm going to let that slide.
欧比旺·肯诺比是《星球大战》中的一个角色
Obi-Wan Kenobi is a character from Star Wars.
他在身体消失后
After his physical demise,
以灵魂形体出现卢克·天行者面前  继续指导他
he comes to Luke Skywalker as his mentor in spirit form.
你的解释让我"豁然开朗"
Well, that... that clears that up.
你一定是来给我建议的
You must be here to give me advice.
这...这装束好奇怪
Well, this... this is weird.
我大多数长袍开口都在后面
Most-most of my robes open in...
方便上厕所
in the back.
这是绝地武士袍
Those are your Jedi robes.
等等  这...
Oh, wait. What...?
这是什么
What-what... what is this?
悠着点玩
Oh! Be careful with that!
太酷了
Oh, neato.
我想...我需要一张创口贴
I'm, uh... I'm going to need a Band-Aid.
你参加了人生第一场葬礼  感觉如何
So...what did you think of your first funeral?
虽然我不想失礼  但葬礼实在有点无聊
Well, I don't want to be a jerk, but it was kind of a bummer.
等我死了  你可以租个蹦蹦城堡办葬礼
Yeah, well, when I die, you can rent a bounce house.
你现在就想"死"这件事吗
You think about dying?
我想得更多的是  怕自己会有遗憾
Well, I think more about if I'd have any regrets.
你的遗憾会是什么
What would you regret?
比如旅行太少
Mm, you know, that I didn't travel more,
冒险太少  只会一门语言
take more risks, learn another language.
你还会克林贡语啊
You know Klingon.
那倒也是
That's true.
不  我是说这是你的遗憾之一
No, I meant that as a regret.
-我刚又想到了一个  -是什么
- I just thought of one more. - What's that?
我遗憾在你求婚的时候  没有说"我愿意"
I regret not saying "Yes" when you asked me to marry you.
那时候时机不对
Well, it just wasn't the right time.
是啊
Yeah.
现在也不是什么好时机
And this is also not the right time.
不准求婚
Do not propose.
什么
What?
我认得那表情  那是你要求婚的表情
I know that face. That's your propose face.
我没打算求婚啊  现在都二比一了
I was not gonna propose. It's already two to one.
什么二比一
What's two to one?
我求过两次婚  你才求过一次  所以是二比一
I proposed twice, you proposed once. Two to one.
天啊   这又不是比赛
Oh, my... It's not a contest.
我不懂你在气什么
I don't know what you're upset about.
-我才是比分落后的那个  -算了
- I'm the one who's losing. - Okay.
那好  如果我现在跟你求婚
Fine. Would you feel better if I propose
给你机会拒绝我第二次  你会好过点吗
so you could turn me down again?
当然会啊
Yeah, I think I would.
好  莱纳德  你愿意娶我吗
Okay. Leonard, will you marry me?
你敢
No, don't you dare.
你快拒绝我  咱俩就扯平了
You reject me right now and tie things up.
这可是一个很重大的决定
It's just such a big decision.
我不想留下任何遗憾
I don't want to have any regrets.
你小时候看过质子教授吗
Did you ever watch Professor Proton when you were a kid?
没有
No.
我爸爸掌控电视
My dad controlled the TV,
所以除非那人是《德州巡警》
so unless someone was a Texas Ranger,
或《帅虎猛龙》里的角色  否则没看过
Jake or the Fatman, we didn't see it.
我也从未看过  但是似乎是他
I never watched him, either, but he seems to be the reason
激发了谢尔顿对科学的兴趣
that Sheldon got interested in science.
我不是  我对科学感兴趣
Not me. I got into science
是因为我总是学校里最矮小的那个
'cause I was always the smallest kid in school,
所以我想如果我成为了科学家
so I thought if I became a scientist,
就可以发明出一种让我变高的药
I could invent a formula that made me taller.
这想法真天真
That's cute.
是啊  曾有一段时间我觉得真的有用
Yeah, I thought it was working for a while,
但结果却发现是我哥哥
but then I found out my brother was just
在量身高的门框上动手脚
lowering the pencil marks on the door frame.
你呢
How about you?
我想应该是在我当女子军那会
Oh, I guess it must have been back when I was in the Girl Sprouts.
女子军
Girl Sprouts?
这是我妈妈为了跟女童军区分  故意取的
My mom made it up as an alternative to the Girl Scouts.
她不想我"像妓女一般
She didn't want me selling cookies
在大街小巷叫卖饼干"
on some street corner "Like a whore."
那怎么会让你科学感兴趣呢
How did that get you into science?
我去图书馆
Oh, I went to the library
拿了一本生物学的书  看看妓女都做什么
and took out a book on biology to see what whores did.
一方面  如果我说"我愿意"
On the one hand, if I say yes...
一点都不好玩
This isn't funny anymore.
快拒绝我  然后我们就扯平了
Just say no so we're done with this.
你愿意还是不愿意娶我
Will you marry me or not?
有意思  你刚是"又"向我求婚了吗
Ooh, interesting. Did you just propose to me again?
-不是  -真的吗
- No. - Really?
因为我刚明明听见  "你愿意娶我吗"
Because I just heard, "Will you marry me?"
一天求两次婚哦
That's two proposals, one day.
看来有人下半辈子都想教孩子
Sounds like someone wants to spend the rest of her life
怎么拼"霍夫斯塔德"这个姓
telling people how to spell the name Hofstadter.
算了  随便你怎么样
You know what? Fine. Do whatever you want.
佩妮  不要生气嘛
Penny, don't get upset.
听着
Here.
我爱你  但我不会娶你
I love you, but, no, I will not marry you.
谢谢
Thank you.
那我们说回第二次求婚
Now, about that second proposal.
一方面...
On the one hand...
我们...我们这是在哪儿
Where... where... where are we?
达戈巴的沼泽地
This is the swampland of Dagobah.
这是卢克接受绝地训练的地方
It's where Luke was trained in the ways of the Jedi.
太可惜了  我还以为是佛罗里达呢
Too bad. I thought it was Florida.
当欧比旺在这里时
When Obi-Wan came to Luke on this very spot,
他给了卢克各种有用的建议
he gave him all sorts of helpful advice.
所以
So, um...
你对我的建议是什么
what do you got for me?
一定
Always...
要签...婚前协议
get... get a prenup.
就这样吗
That's it?
我还以为你来找我有更深远的意义呢
I thought there'd be more of a reason why you're here.
那你觉得我为什么来找你
Well, why-why do you think I'm here?
我想可能跟你最近去世的事有关吧
I suppose it has something to do with your recent passing.
这是...  你第一次
Is-is this the... the first time
失去了跟你亲近的人吗
you've lost, you know, someone close to you?
不  不是
Oh, no. No.
我已经经历过跟11代的神秘博士道别了
I've already had to say good-bye to 11 Dr. Whos.
我也比我好几任医生[博士]活得长
Yeah, I've-I've outlived a few of my doctors, too.
当然  我的爷爷在我5岁的时候去世了
Of course, my grandfather died when I was five.
我父亲在我14岁的时候去世
My father died when I was 14.
节哀顺变
I'm... I'm sorry about that.
现在你也过世了
And now you're gone, too.
感觉所有我崇拜的男性都去世了
It's like all the men I've looked up to have gone away.
你知道  其实...
Well, you know, it's...
是可以对他们的去世感到难过的
it's okay to... to be sad about them.
只是你要记住  你也得
Just... just make sure, you know, you appreciate
珍惜那些还在世的亲朋好友
those who... who are still there for you.
我很珍惜他们啊
But I do appreciate them.
既然如此
Well, then,
那我在这破沼泽
what am I doing in a swamp...
穿得像罗宾汉里的塔克修士干啥
...dressed like Friar Tuck?
珍惜眼前人  谢尔顿
Appreciate them, Sheldon.
兄弟
Hey, buddy.
听说你今天听不开心  你没事吧
Heard you're having a rough day. You all right?
我没事
I'm okay.
丧礼如何
How was the funeral?
挺好的
It was nice, you know.
很多人都来了
A lot of people showed up,
说了很多他生平的好事
told some great stories about him.
你知道亚瑟的儿子是个高中科学老...
Did you know that Arthur's son is a high school sci...?
他们要开始看第六部了
Hey, the guys are about to start Jedi.
你想去看吗
You want to go watch?
想
I do.
但我得先让他们从第一部开始看
After I make them go back and watch one through five first.
谢尔顿  那我们得花一整晚呢
Sheldon, that-that'll take us all night.
的确
That's true.
幸好我小睡了一会
Oh, it's a good thing I had a nap.
加加的一些肢体搞笑画面
Boy, some of the physical comedy
真的是有点看不下去啊
with Jar Jar is a little tough to watch.
至少第二部里  已经让他收敛了
At least they toned him down in the second one.
是啊  这角色真蠢
Yeah, he is pretty stupid.
我们才能说他  你没资格
Hey, we can say it. You can't.
大伙们
Hey, guys.
星球大战日快乐
Happy Star Wars Day!
-死星蛋糕  -是啊
- A Death Star cake! - Yeah.
我们希望它能让你开心点
We were hoping it might cheer you up.
虽然我们因为烤蛋糕  错过了电影
And even though it meant we had to miss the movies,
但我们还是想一起同乐同乐
we could still be part of the fun.
你完全没错过
Well, you didn't miss anything.
我们刚从头重看
We just started over.
我去他妈的
Son of a bitch.
你回来啦
You're back.
是啊  貌似...
Yeah, apparently, um,
貌似你需要我的任何时候  我就会出现
I'm here whenever... when-whenever you need me.
真好
That's nice.
你好我不好
May-Maybe for you.
那我现在为什么需要你
Why do I need you now?
就我看来
Well, as near as I could tell,
你在看《星球大战》的过程中睡着了
you-you fell asleep watching Star Wars,
你现在是梦见自己正在看《星球大战》
and now you're-you're dreaming you're watching Star Wars.
所以呢
So?
这样有什么问题吗
I mean, don't-don't you see a problem there?
你觉得
I mean, how-how
这么使用你在世有限的时间好吗
you're spending your limited time on Earth?
没啥不好啊
Not at all.
行  那祝你睡得愉快
Okay, good luck to you.